Calculation of a Six Sigma Performance Baseline
Welcome back to this session on baselines. Recall from the last time
where we looked at five CTQ’s, CTQ 1, 2, 3, 4,  and 5.
Each having an inherent capability of Three Sigma.
Thereby providing a yield of 93.32%.
Within the matrix, you'll recall, we looked at the quality outcome
of inspection or test and the yield result.
One if it yielded, zero if it did not. Thus, we have a simple count of output.
In other words, how many yielded? In this case, 720 out of a thousand.
Thereby providing a throughput yield of 72%.  Simple output over input.
Normalized yield being 93.64%, which the 72% raised to the quantity 1/5.
Since there are five CTQ’s.
That converts to a Sigma capability of 3.03.
By simulating, hitting F9,
we’re able to create multiple cases of a thousand.
Recall, that's what we are producing in the simulation.
A thousand individual cases, of five CTQ’s each.
Where each case is a unit of product. Now, I can change the Sigma capability.
Let's suppose the first CTQ had Two Sigma, Three Sigma, Four Sigma.
A Five Sigma capability and another Two Sigma.
In this case we can see the output would be 435
good units produced out of the thousand.
Resulting in an average, or normalized as we would call it, Sigma,
that constitutes the typical Sigma capability per CTQ.
So, it's kind of like an average. We can see that it's 2.52.
Repeated simulations, by repeatedly pushing F9,
generates new random numbers, producing another simulation.
And you can see that it's changing. This is a simple means to perform simulation.
We could also simulate the Sigma. We could scale the Sigma.
And put in random Sigma's, and see how it results.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.